Finding Aid for John R. Stiles Papers, 1958-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John R. Stiles papers 1958-1965
Stiles, John R.
2 linear ft.
86112 Aa 2
Grand Rapids, Michigan, businessman and Republican campaign official. Correspondence, reports, newspaper clippings and campaign materials concerning the Warren Commission's investigation of the assassination of President John F. Kennedy, the writing of the book, Portrait of the Assassin with Gerald Ford, and his activities as campaign manager for Paul Bagwell for governor in 1958, and as field director of the Richard Nixon for President campaign in 1960.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by John R. Stiles (donor no. 5557 ) in 1974.
The collection is open to research.
John R. Stiles was a Grand Rapids, Michigan businessman and Republican Party campaign official. He served as Gerald Ford's first campaign manager in 1948 when Ford unseated the incumbent. He was a member of Paul Bagwell's campaign for governor in 1958, and in 1960, he served as field director of the Nixon-for-President campaign. When President Johnson appointed Congressman Ford to serve on the Warren Commission, Ford turned to Stiles to serve as his special assistant. Following the conclusion of the Warren Commission, Ford and Stiles worked jointly on their history of their work with the Commission, published as Portrait of the Assassin (1965).
The collection documents John R. Stiles' work with the Warren Commission and the state Republican Party. The collection has been arranged into the following series: Portrait of the Assassin drafts; Warren Commission File; and Republican Party Political Files.
Subjects:
Bagwell, Paul D.; Grand Rapids (Mich.); Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-; Republican Party (Mich.); United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; United States--Politics and government--1963-1969.; United States--Politics and government--1961-1963.; United States. Warren Commission.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Contributors:
Ford, Gerald R., 1913-
- Portrait of the Assassin drafts
  - Chapter drafts, 45 folders (Box 1)
  - Working drafts of Portrait of the Assassin (Box 1)
- Warren Commission File, 1964
  (collected research materials used in the Ford-Stiles book)
  - F.B.I. Report on the assassination (Box 1)
  - Supplemental F.B.I. report on the Assassination (Box 1)
  - Schedules of the Commission (Box 1)
  - Articles on the Assassination (Box 1)
  - Suggested questions to be asked of witnesses, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Chronologies of Oswald's activities, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Abstracts from depositions (Box 1)
  - Chapter outlines for Portrait of the Assassin (Box 1)
  - Check-off lists (Box 1)
  - Chronological File on Oswald's activities, October 4-November 22, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Conclusions (Box 1)
  - Plot theories (Box 1)
  - Marina Oswald's character (Box 1)
  - Lee Oswald's character (Box 1)
  - Separations of Lee and Marina Oswald (Box 1)
  - Trip to Dallas (Box 1)
  - Events while in the Marine Corps (Box 1)
  - Troubles at Home (Box 1)
  - Russian Colony (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - F.B.I. Visual Aids (Box 2)
  - F.B.I. Exhibits, 3 volumes (Box 2)
- Republican Party Political Files
  - Paul Bagwell for Governor File, 1958
    - Report to the Republican National Committee, November 1958 (Box 2)
    - Bagwell Bluebook on Highways (Box 2)
    - Campaign Schedules (Box 2)
    - Campaign Committees and Chairmen (Box 2)
    - Voting Statistics (Box 2)
    - Issues (Box 2)
    - Small Business Administration (Box 2)
    - Saint Lawrence Seaway Festival (Box 2)
    - List-of delegates and alternates to the Republican State Convention (Box 2)
  - Republican State Central Committee File, 1959-1960
    - Victory in '60 outline (Box 2)
    - State Central Subcommittees (Box 2)
    - Suggestions of members, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Suggestions of the Staff (Box 2)
    - Past national convention delegations (Box 2)
    - List of delegates and alternates to the Republican state convention, May 1960 (Box 2)
    - List of delegates and alternates to the Republican state convention, August 1960 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Newspaper clippings, Undated and February-October 1960, 7 folders (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 2)
  - Campaign for State Republican Chairman File, 1961
    - Campaign leaflets (Box 2)
    - Lists of delegates, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - List of delegates and alternates to the Republican state convention (Box 2)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 2)
  - Oregon delegate and presidential primary laws, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Speech on "How to steal a presidential nomination" 1965 (Box 2)